

João Pedro Dias

ENGINEER. DEVELOPER. RESEARCHER. AMATEUR PHOTOGRAPHER.

Porto, Portugal

☑ jpmdias@fe.up.pt | ♠ jpdias.me | ☑ jpdias | 匝 joaopdias | У jpd1as | ⑤ jpdias

Summary

Current Researcher at INESC TEC and pursuing a PhD degree in Informatics Engineering. Graduated from the Integrated Masters in Informatics and Computing Engineering, I'm passionate about technology, with a special focus on security and privacy, web development, data mining & Internet of Things. Besides that, I'm also an amateur photographer, football player, book lover and science addict.

Education

Doctoral Program in Informatics Engineering - ProDEI (PhD)

Porto, Portugal

FACULTY OF ENGINEERING, UNIVERSITY OF PORTO (FEUP)

2016-Exp. 2020

• Title: Towards a Reference Architecture for Orchestrating Large-Scale Internet of Things' Systems using Visual Programming Languages

Master in Informatics and Computing Engineering - MIEIC (MSc)

Porto, Portugal

FACULTY OF ENGINEERING, UNIVERSITY OF PORTO (FEUP)

2011-2016

- GPA: 15 out of 20
- Volunteer at Semana Profissão: Engenheiro (SPE) 2014 & 2016

Sciences and Technologies

Amarante, Porto, Portugal

Externato de Vila Meã

2008-2011

GPA: 17 out of 20

Experience

INESC TEC – Institute for Systems and Computer Engineering, Technology and Science | CSIG – Centre for Information Systems and Computer Graphics

University of Porto, Porto, Portugal

RESEARCHER

May 2017 -

• Researching in the area of Internet of Things, with special focus on Blockchain and Healthcare applications, in the scope of the project NanoSTIMA: Macro-to-Nano Human Sensing: Towards Integrated Multimodal Health Monitoring and Analytics.

LIACC - Artificial Intelligence and Computer Science Laboratory

University of Porto, Porto, Portugal

RESEARCHER

Sept. 2016 – Apr. 2017

- Researching data representation and data mining applications on railway transportation systems in the scope of the project PEDDIR: Weigth in Motion and Wheels Defect Detection.
- Technologies: MongoDB, Python and Web Development | Project details: www.peddir.eu & www.in2rail.eu

ShiftForward, S.A. Porto, Portugal

SUMMER ENGINEERING INTERN

Jul. 2015 – Aug. 2015

- · Development of a Deploy Logger Service, a service for documenting and recording the release of new product versions over time.
- Technologies: Scala and Backbone. js | Project details: shiftforward.github.io/malamute/

Centro Hospitalar do Tâmega e Sousa, E.P.E.

Penafiel, Porto, Portugal

IT DEPARTMENT INTERNSHIP

Jul. 2014 - Aug. 2014

- · Development of an expedient management system for replacing the existent system based on paper archives.
- Technologies: ${\tt MySQL}$ and ${\tt PHP}$

Additional Training

2017 **Project Management,** ERASMUS+ Mobility for teaching FEUP, Porto, Portugal

2016 AWS Technical Essentials Online, Amazon Web Services – Training and Certification Online

2015 **Practical Workshop in Agile Project Management,** Strongstep - Innovation in UPTEC, Porto, Portugal

Software Quality
2015 **CERN Spring Campus**, CERN - European Organization for Nuclear Research

Lisbon, Portugal

2014 M101JS: MongoDB for Node.js Developers, MongoDB University

Online

Skills

Programming Python **=** • Node.JS **=** • C/C++ **=** • Scala **=** • Java **=** • C# **=** • PHP **=** Web Technologies HTML5 ≡ • CSS ≡ • JavaScript ≡ • Laravel(PHP) ≡ • Flask(Python) ≡ • Bootstrap(CSS) ≡ • jQuery(JS) ≡ **Databases** MySQL **=** • PostgreSQL **=** • InfluxDB **=** • MongoDB **=**

Others Arduino ≡ • Git ≡ • Android ≡ • Windows Apps ≡ • Docker ≡ • Computer Security ≡ • LaTeX ≡

Languages Portuguese (Mother-tongue) **=** • English **=**

Publications ____

CONFERENCE ARTICLES (PEER-REVIEWED)

2017 Towards a Framework for Agent-based Simulation of User Behaviour in E-Commerce Porto, Portugal **Context**, Duarte Duarte, João Pedro Dias, Hugo Sereno Ferreira and Zaf. Kokkinogenis 15th International Conference on Practical Applications of Agents and Multi-Agent Systems (PAAMS'17) { DOI: 10.1007/978-3-319-61578-3_3 }

2017 Automating the Extraction of Static Content and Dynamic Behaviour from Madeira, Portugal e-Commerce Websites, João Pedro Dias and Hugo Sereno Ferreira

8th International Conference on Ambient Systems, Networks and Technologies (ANT'17) { DOI: 10.1016/j.procs.2017.05.355 }

2017 A hands-on approach on botnets for behavior exploration, João Pedro Dias, José Porto, Portugal Pedro Pinto and José Magalhães Cruz

2nd International Conference on Internet of Things, Big Data and Security (IoTBDS 2017) { DOI: 10.5220/0006392404630469 }

OTHERS

2017 Automating the Extraction of Static Content and Dynamic Behaviour from Porto, Portugal e-Commerce Websites, João Pedro Dias and Hugo Sereno Ferreira

10th Meeting of Young Researchers of University of Porto (IJUP 2017)

2016 A hands-on approach on botnets for a learning purpose, João Pedro Dias, José Pedro Porto, Portugal Pinto and José Magalhães Cruz

9th Meeting of Young Researchers of University of Porto (IJUP 2016)

DISSERTATIONS

2016 Reverse Engineering Static Content and Dynamic Behaviour of E-Commerce Sites for Porto, Portugal Fun and Profit, Supervised by Hugo Sereno Ferreira | Grade of 17 out of 20.

Master's Dissertation, Faculty of Engineering, University of Porto { ID: 10216/85374 }

Educational & Scientific Activities

MASTER'S DISSERTATION CO-SUPERVISING

2017 Interoperability In Software Applications For Smart Cities: Towards A Reference Architecture by José Pedro Pinto, Supervised by Prof. Rosaldo Rossetti, Masters in Informatics and Computing Engineering, Faculty of Engineering, University of Porto

Porto, Portugal

PROGRAM COMMITTEES & REVIEWS

2017 **PC Member**, IEEE S3C 2017 - 2017 IEEE Summer School on Smart Cities Natal, Brazil 2017 IEEE Intelligent Vehicles Symposium (IEEE IV'17), Reviewer California, USA 2017 IEEE 20th International Conference on Intelligent Transportation Systems (IEEE Yokohama, Japan ITSC 2017), Reviewer

Conference Organization

2017	Web Communication Co-chair, ACM CarSys 2017 – The Second ACM International	Utah, USA
	Workshop on Smart, Autonomous, and Connected Vehicular Systems and Services, part	
	of the The 23 rd Annual International Conference on Mobile Computing and Networking	
	(MobiCom 2017)	
2017	Advisor Board Member, Talk a Bit – Technology Conference, 5th Edition (2017)	Porto, Portugal
2016	Conference Chair, Talk a Bit – Technology Conference, 4th Edition (2016)	Porto, Portugal
2016	Web Communication Co-chair, 2016 IEEE 19th International Conference on Intelligent	Rio de Janeiro, Brazil
	Transportation Systems (ITSC 2016)	
2014	Student Volunteer, Inter-University Programming Marathon (MIUP 2014)	FEUP, Porto, Portugal
2014	Student Volunteer, INForum - Symposion on Informatics (INForum 2014)	Porto, Portugal

Invited Talks & Workshops

OPOSEC Meetup: [0x33] - The Meet

Porto, Portugal

Apr. 2016

HOSTED BY BLIP.PT

• Present the work A hands-on approach on botnets for a learning purpose.

Share World Seminar 2015 – "Europe vs. Asia: Grass Is Always Greener On The Other Side"

FEUP, Porto, Portugal

March 2015

 ${\sf Hosted} \; {\sf By} \; {\sf ShARE} \; {\sf Global} \; {\sf Student} \; {\sf Think} \; {\sf Tank}$

• Workshop on How To Create Your First Personal Webpage.

Pro Bono Activity

ACADEMIC

IEEE University of Porto Student Branch

Porto, Portugal

STUDENT MEMBER

2012 - 2016

EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE (SECRETARY)

2013 - 2015

- As a voluntary member I had organized and co-organized some workshops (*C#*, *Photography*, *MEX*, *Web Development*) and other events including *IEEE Day*, *IEEEXtreme* and *IEEEmadC*.
- As secretary I was also responsable for mantain the minutes of all meetings and other paperwork.

HUMANITARIAN

Luz da Vida Youth Group

Amarante, Porto, Portugal

FOUNDER MEMBER

2009 – 2011

· Founder and former active member, I had taken part of large number of activities on behalf of the village community.

Honors & Awards

INTERNATIONAL

2017	847 (of 2815) , Google Hash Code 2017, <i>hashcode.withgoogle.com</i>	Online – Porto, Portugal
2015	189th (of 2477) , IEEEXtreme – 24h Programming Competition 9.0, <i>sites.ieee.org/xtreme</i>	Online – Porto, Portugal
2014	Honorable Mention , IEEEmadC – Mobile Application Dev. Contest, <i>ieeemadc.org</i>	Online – Porto, Portugal
2013	126th (of 7500) , IEEEXtreme – 24h Programming Competition 7.0, <i>sites.ieee.org/xtreme</i>	Online – Porto, Portugal
2013	2nd Place , European BEST Engineering Competition, <i>ebec.best.eu.org</i>	Warsaw, Poland

DOMESTIC

2011	1 st Place, PmatE Mat12 – Mathematics Competition, <i>pmate.ua.pt</i>	University of Aveiro, Portugal
2009	2nd Place , PmatE Fis12 – Physics Competition, <i>pmate.ua.pt</i>	University of Aveiro, Portugal